<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><document>
<properties>
<author email="mikkey@sourceforge.net">Miguel Griffa</author>
<title>PMD Rulesets index</title>
</properties>
<body>
<section name="Current Rulesets">
<p>List of rulesets and rules contained in each ruleset.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<a href="#Basic_JSF">Basic JSF</a>: Rules concerning basic JSF guidelines.  </li>
<li>
<a href="#Basic_JSP">Basic JSP</a>: Rules concerning basic JSP guidelines.</li>
</ul>
<a name="Basic_JSF"/>
<subsection name="Basic JSF (jsp)">
<ul>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic-jsf.html#DontNestJsfInJstlIteration">DontNestJsfInJstlIteration</a>: Do not nest JSF component custom actions inside a custom action that iterates over its body.     </li>
</ul>
</subsection>
<a name="Basic_JSP"/>
<subsection name="Basic JSP (jsp)">
<ul>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoLongScripts">NoLongScripts</a>: Scripts should be part of Tag Libraries, rather than part of JSP pages.		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoScriptlets">NoScriptlets</a>: Scriptlets should be factored into Tag Libraries or JSP	declarations, rather than being part of JSP pages.		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoInlineStyleInformation">NoInlineStyleInformation</a>:  Style information should be put in CSS files, not in JSPs. Therefore, don't use &lt;B&gt; or &lt;FONT&gt; tags, or attributes like "align='center'". 		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoClassAttribute">NoClassAttribute</a>: Do not use an attribute called 'class'. Use "styleclass" for CSS styles.		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoJspForward">NoJspForward</a>: Do not do a forward from within a JSP file.		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#IframeMissingSrcAttribute">IframeMissingSrcAttribute</a>: IFrames which are missing a src element can cause security information popups in IE if you are accessing the pagethrough SSL. See http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=kb;EN-US;Q261188		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoHtmlComments">NoHtmlComments</a>: 			In a production system, HTML comments increase the payload			between the application server to the client, and serve			little other purpose. Consider switching to JSP comments.		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#DuplicateJspImports">DuplicateJspImports</a>: Avoid duplicate import statements inside JSP's. 		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#JspEncoding">JspEncoding</a>: 			A missing 'meta' tag or page directive will trigger this rule, as well as a non-UTF-8 charset.            		</li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoInlineScript">NoInlineScript</a>:             Avoid inlining HTML script content.  Consider externalizing the HTML script using the 'src' attribute on the &lt;script&gt; element.Externalized script could be reused between pages.  Browsers can also cache the script, reducing overall download bandwidth.                    </li>
<li>
<a href="jsp/basic.html#NoUnsanitizedJSPExpression">NoUnsanitizedJSPExpression</a>: Avoid using expressions without escaping / sanitizing. This could lead to cross site scripting - as the expressionwould be interpreted by the browser directly (e.g. "&lt;script&gt;alert('hello');&lt;/script&gt;").        </li>
</ul>
</subsection>
</section>
</body>
</document>
